<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Brian Cohan</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2019-05-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Detroit Metro Airport Tunnel Fire Modeling</title><link href="/detroit-metro-airport-tunnel-fire-modeling.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-05-16:/detroit-metro-airport-tunnel-fire-modeling.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for evaluating exhaust needs in short road tunnels by the airport. Two tunnels had different exhaust designs that needed to be evaluated for structural integrity and human tenability per NFPA 502.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="FDS"></category><category term="PBD"></category></entry><entry><title>University of Rochester Medical Center - Hood Exhaust</title><link href="/university-of-rochester-medical-center-hood-exhaust.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-05-06:/university-of-rochester-medical-center-hood-exhaust.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for determining the risk of fire on the exhaust system for medical lab benches. The models focused on several fire scenarios to determine the impact on the PVC exhaust piping.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="FDS"></category><category term="PBD"></category><category term="University"></category></entry><entry><title>GMU Johnson Center - Egress Study</title><link href="/gmu-johnson-center-egress-study.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-03-04:/gmu-johnson-center-egress-study.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for evaluating the egress capabilities of the student center. A change in the use of large areas on upper floors would require additional egress capacity. Egress modeling was used to determine a new occupant load that could safely evacuate the building while tenability was maintained in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for evaluating the egress capabilities of the student center. A change in the use of large areas on upper floors would require additional egress capacity. Egress modeling was used to determine a new occupant load that could safely evacuate the building while tenability was maintained in the atrium.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Pathfinder"></category><category term="PBD"></category><category term="University"></category></entry><entry><title>NNS - Dust Hazard Analysis</title><link href="/nns-dust-hazard-analysis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-02-27:/nns-dust-hazard-analysis.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for evaluating several processes that generate explosible dust. Twelve buildings were evaluated in processes from cutting to sandblasting, to powder coating. Explosion propagation was considered, and recommendations were made to reduce the risk of dust explosions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Special Hazard"></category></entry><entry><title>Carvana Vending Machine Structural Steel Analysis</title><link href="/carvana-vending-machine-structural-steel-analysis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-02-05:/carvana-vending-machine-structural-steel-analysis.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for developing performance-based criteria and modeling fires in an eight-story Carvana Vending Machine. Each level has four cars surrounding a central hoistway. The goal was to determine the suppression requirements to prevent additional cars from igniting.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="FDS"></category><category term="PBD"></category><category term="Sprinkler"></category></entry><entry><title>NNS - Foundry Exhaust</title><link href="/nns-foundry-exhaust.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-12-18:/nns-foundry-exhaust.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for designing a plan to prevent sparks from an electric arc furnace igniting air filters in the exhaust system. The design included a redundant approach of passive spark cooling and active spark detection and extinguishing system.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Special Hazard"></category></entry><entry><title>Element Detroit at the Metropolitan - Starwood Survey</title><link href="/element-detroit-at-the-metropolitan-starwood-survey.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-11-30:/element-detroit-at-the-metropolitan-starwood-survey.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for performing a site survey for a historic building that was being renovated into a hotel. The survey was performed per the Starwood requirements by Marriott.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life Safety Code"></category></entry><entry><title>Four Points by Sheraton Cleveland-Eastlake - Starwood Survey</title><link href="/four-points-by-sheraton-cleveland-eastlake-starwood-survey.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-11-15:/four-points-by-sheraton-cleveland-eastlake-starwood-survey.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for performing a site survey for a hotel renovation project. The survey was performed per the Starwood requirements by Marriott.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life Safety Code"></category></entry><entry><title>GMU Robinson Hall - Atrium Exhaust</title><link href="/gmu-robinson-hall-atrium-exhaust.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-10-26:/gmu-robinson-hall-atrium-exhaust.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for performing a rational analysis of an atrium exhaust system per the Virginia Uniform Statewide Building Code.  The rational analysis involved a series of computational fluid dynamics models to determine the required mechanical exhaust rate and duration of operation for multiple atrium configurations based on evacuation …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for performing a rational analysis of an atrium exhaust system per the Virginia Uniform Statewide Building Code.  The rational analysis involved a series of computational fluid dynamics models to determine the required mechanical exhaust rate and duration of operation for multiple atrium configurations based on evacuation models.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="FDS"></category><category term="PBD"></category><category term="University"></category></entry><entry><title>Solenis Groundwater Data Processing</title><link href="/solenis-groundwater-data-processing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-10-26:/solenis-groundwater-data-processing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Data Analyst responsible for processing groundwater data. Water levels were recorded every 30 minutes in a dozen wells. The data was compiled to show the groundwater elevation over time and to generate groundwater contour maps. A series of contour maps were stitched into animation to show how the groundwater was …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Data Analyst responsible for processing groundwater data. Water levels were recorded every 30 minutes in a dozen wells. The data was compiled to show the groundwater elevation over time and to generate groundwater contour maps. A series of contour maps were stitched into animation to show how the groundwater was behaving over time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Surfer"></category></entry><entry><title>GMU - Housing Occupancy Study</title><link href="/gmu-housing-occupancy-study.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-09-05:/gmu-housing-occupancy-study.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for evaluating all 40+ GMU housing buildings to determine how many residents could fit into each floor. The analysis compared Virginia housing requirements, egress capacity, and plumbing fixture capacity.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life Safety Code"></category><category term="University"></category></entry><entry><title>NVCC Building CC - Smoke Detector Modifications</title><link href="/nvcc-building-cc-smoke-detector-modifications.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-08-24:/nvcc-building-cc-smoke-detector-modifications.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for providing the design and specifications for fire alarm modifications. Drop ceilings were installed in several classrooms which removed beam pockets and resulted in the removal of many smoke detectors.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Fire Alarm"></category><category term="University"></category></entry><entry><title>Fuquay-Varina High School Gymnasium</title><link href="/fuquay-varina-high-school-gymnasium.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-05-18:/fuquay-varina-high-school-gymnasium.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for validating previous fire modeling efforts in the school’s gymnasium. The previous efforts modeled plastic bleachers catching fire below steel beams that were not rated. The design of the bleachers changed, resulting in taking another look at the results.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="FDS"></category><category term="PBD"></category></entry><entry><title>LeJeune Steel Paint Spill Analysis</title><link href="/lejeune-steel-paint-spill-analysis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-04-25:/lejeune-steel-paint-spill-analysis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for analyzing hazards associated with a large paint spray area in a steel manufacturing facility. The primary hazard evaluated was large quantities of flammable liquids used to paint large steel members in an un-sprinklered area. Multiple pool fire scenarios were evaluated to determine if tenability and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for analyzing hazards associated with a large paint spray area in a steel manufacturing facility. The primary hazard evaluated was large quantities of flammable liquids used to paint large steel members in an un-sprinklered area. Multiple pool fire scenarios were evaluated to determine if tenability and structural steel goals would be met without the installation of new sprinklers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="CFAST"></category><category term="PBD"></category></entry><entry><title>SSA National Computing Center - Atrium Exhaust</title><link href="/ssa-national-computing-center-atrium-exhaust.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-03-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-03-29:/ssa-national-computing-center-atrium-exhaust.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for creating the initial design for an atrium smoke exhaust system. The National Computing Center atrium is five stories high and has open lounges on each floor which generated a unique geometry. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="FDS"></category><category term="GSA"></category></entry><entry><title>UR - Alice Jepson Theater</title><link href="/ur-alice-jepson-theater.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-01-05:/ur-alice-jepson-theater.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer assisting in reviewing a performance-based exhaust system in a theater. The system was designed to protect occupants from a fire in place of a water curtain that was frequently subjected to mechanical damage.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="PBD"></category><category term="University"></category></entry><entry><title>National Air and Space Museum - Egress Analysis</title><link href="/national-air-and-space-museum-egress-analysis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-11-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-11-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-11-02:/national-air-and-space-museum-egress-analysis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for egress modeling. Pathfinder was used to simulate a full occupant load evacuating all three floors plus the basement. Scenarios were developed corresponding with the design fires required in NFPA 101 to assess blocked exits. In addition to the egress modeling, he reviewed the egress calculations …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for egress modeling. Pathfinder was used to simulate a full occupant load evacuating all three floors plus the basement. Scenarios were developed corresponding with the design fires required in NFPA 101 to assess blocked exits. In addition to the egress modeling, he reviewed the egress calculations for accuracy and determining sufficient egress capacity.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life Safety Code"></category><category term="Pathfinder"></category><category term="PBD"></category></entry><entry><title>GHD</title><link href="https://www.ghd.com/en-us" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:www.ghd.com,2017-10-17:/en-us</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Working at GHD&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Building 1595 Upgrades</title><link href="/building-1595-upgrades.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-01-01:/building-1595-upgrades.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer assisting with hydrant flow tests to determine the water supply for a new sprinkler system design.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Sprinkler"></category></entry><entry><title>Appendix R Solutions</title><link href="http://ars-corp.net/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:ars-corp.net,2011-04-01:/</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Working at ARS&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Beaver Valley Power Station - 86-10s</title><link href="/beaver-valley-power-station-86-10s.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2011-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2011-01-01:/beaver-valley-power-station-86-10s.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for evaluating code deficiencies under NRC Generic Letter No. 86-10, Implementation of Fire Protection Requirements. The evaluation considered actual plant conditions to determine if an equivalent or adequate level of protection was maintained.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Nuclear"></category></entry><entry><title>Davis-Besse Nuclear Power Station, Unit 1 - FPRA</title><link href="/davis-besse-nuclear-power-station-unit-1-fpra.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2011-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2011-01-01:/davis-besse-nuclear-power-station-unit-1-fpra.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for performing fire models as part of a Fire Probabilistic Risk Assessment (FPRA). The FPRA required analyzing a large number of ignition sources for impact on nuclear operations. Fire Dynamics Tools were used to model thousands of scenarios throughout the power plant.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="FDTs"></category><category term="FPRA"></category><category term="Nuclear"></category></entry><entry><title>Doel Nuclear Power Plant - FPRA</title><link href="/doel-nuclear-power-plant-fpra.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2011-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2011-01-01:/doel-nuclear-power-plant-fpra.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for reviewing fire models used in a Fire Probabilistic Risk Assessment (FPRA). The FPRA required analyzing a large number of ignition sources throughout multiple power plants for impact on nuclear operations. The analysis required a combination of fire modeling software.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="CFAST"></category><category term="FDS"></category><category term="FDTs"></category><category term="FPRA"></category><category term="Nuclear"></category></entry><entry><title>Edwin I. Hatch Nuclear Power Plant - FPRA</title><link href="/edwin-i-hatch-nuclear-power-plant-fpra.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2011-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2011-01-01:/edwin-i-hatch-nuclear-power-plant-fpra.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for performing fire models as part of a Fire Probabilistic Risk Assessment (FPRA). The FPRA required analyzing a large number of ignition sources for impact on nuclear operations. Fire Dynamics Tools were used to model thousands of scenarios throughout the multi-unit power plant.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="FDTs"></category><category term="FPRA"></category><category term="Nuclear"></category></entry><entry><title>Enrico Fermi II NPP - FPRA</title><link href="/enrico-fermi-ii-npp-fpra.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2011-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2011-01-01:/enrico-fermi-ii-npp-fpra.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for performing fire models as part of a Fire Probabilistic Risk Assessment (FPRA). The FPRA required analyzing a large number of ignition sources for impact on nuclear operations. Fire Dynamics Tools were used to model thousands of scenarios throughout the power plant.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="FDTs"></category><category term="FPRA"></category><category term="Nuclear"></category></entry><entry><title>Enrico Fermi II NPP - HPCI Pump Room Analysis</title><link href="/enrico-fermi-ii-npp-hpci-pump-room-analysis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2011-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2011-01-01:/enrico-fermi-ii-npp-hpci-pump-room-analysis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for demonstrating that an adequate level of protection exists with variations in sprinkler and fire alarm systems designs. Fire Dynamics Simulator was used to model the hazards in fire compartments to determine if modifications were required or to provide a performance-based justification for the existing configuration …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for demonstrating that an adequate level of protection exists with variations in sprinkler and fire alarm systems designs. Fire Dynamics Simulator was used to model the hazards in fire compartments to determine if modifications were required or to provide a performance-based justification for the existing configuration.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="FDS"></category><category term="Nuclear"></category><category term="Sprinkler"></category></entry><entry><title>Mixed Oxide Facility Detection Analysis</title><link href="/mixed-oxide-facility-detection-analysis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2011-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2011-01-01:/mixed-oxide-facility-detection-analysis.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for generating fire models to determine smoke detector coverage requirements. Fire Dynamics Simulator (FDS) and Consolidated Fire and Smoke Transport (CFAST) were used to ensure detection met performance objectives for sensitive areas.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="CFAST"></category><category term="FDS"></category><category term="Fire Alarm"></category><category term="Nuclear"></category></entry><entry><title>Perry Nuclear Power Plant - Containment Detection</title><link href="/perry-nuclear-power-plant-containment-detection.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2011-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2011-01-01:/perry-nuclear-power-plant-containment-detection.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for determining the effectiveness of an alternate means of detection. Due to harsh conditions, wiring for a detection system had degraded. Fire Dynamics Simulator was used to determine if the other detection systems in the area would provide reasonable coverage.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="FDS"></category><category term="Fire Alarm"></category><category term="Nuclear"></category></entry><entry><title>Westinghouse - Cabinet Fire Propagation</title><link href="/westinghouse-cabinet-fire-propagation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2011-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:None,2011-01-01:/westinghouse-cabinet-fire-propagation.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fire Protection Engineer responsible for evaluating fire spread between suited electrical cabinets. Fire Dynamics Simulator was used to evaluate temperatures inside a cabinet due to a fire inside an adjacent cabinet.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="FDS"></category><category term="Nuclear"></category></entry><entry><title>University of Maryland</title><link href="https://fpe.umd.edu/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2011-02-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:fpe.umd.edu,2010-09-01:/</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Working at UMD&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>University of Maryland</title><link href="https://fpe.umd.edu/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2009-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:fpe.umd.edu,2009-09-01:/</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Working at UMD&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Hughes Associates, Inc.</title><link href="https://www.jensenhughes.com/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2010-08-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Brian Cohan</name></author><id>tag:www.jensenhughes.com,2008-03-01:/</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Working at HAI&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>